

Fatai Balogun

Frontend Engineer

Phone: +234 8062 870 354

Website: https://fatai-balogun-portfolio.netlify.app

Email: fatai.balogun12@gmail.com

Software Engineer with a broad set of skills applicable across different sectors and roles. Experienced Solution Architect and Full-stack Developer focused on smart product engineering using agile methods. With a strong drive for excellence through positive thinking. An enthusiastic achiever with a solid background in software development. Full-stack, well-rounded, multilingual, culturally aware professional with a unique ability to relate to diverse clients with various business needs. Highly skilled in solving technical, financial, and business problems for clients and other stakeholders. Committed to improving the quality of life via coding.

EXPERIENCE

Brindocorp April 2021 - current

Software Engineer

I worked with a team of excited problem solvers, where we build various products for our clients.

- I worked on Brindocorp's website from scratch till finish, implement the auth feature, admin dashboard, the landing page, etc
- I revamped the Adereal web app from an electronic store to a food-mile store
- I mentor interns at Brindocorp
- I collaborated with the product manager, product designer, stakeholders, and other team members at various stages of our build process to drive our projects to successful completion.

A handful of Tool was used such as Git, Github, Asana, Reactjs, NextJs, Chakra-UI, GSAP, Boostrap, SASS to mention a few.

Stutern Feb 2021 - March 2021

Frontend Teaching Assistant

I worked with a frontend tutor and a dozen of students to build various fun projects.

- · I reinforce lessons by tutoring and mentoring individual students or small groups assigned to me
- I assisted the lead instructor In reviewing all projects submitted by learners, develop new project ideas, ensure learners' final projects are
 presentable as portfolios
- I check-in group calls with learners fortnightly and monthly AMA sessions twice a month.

A handful of Tool was used such as Git, Github, Trello, Slack, Codepen, Reactjs, Boostrap, SASS to mention a few.

Freelancer Jan 2019 - current

Code Mentor

- I Taught the latest and in-demand skills in Web development to my students.
- I Used coordination and planning skills to achieve results according to schedule.
- I did not only unblock my students when they encounter a bottleneck in a timely fashion, but I also ensure to tell them the reason

for the error.

• I leverage tools like Zoom, Trello, Git & Github, Codepen, and Slack to bring my students up to date.

Andela July 2018 - October 2018

Software Engineer

I worked in a team of six developers for building Author's Heaven Project.

- Actively participated in all levels of the Software Development Life Cycle
- Collaborate with Product Manager to review product designs and generate/break down technical specifications for new product features.
- I build, design, and maintain web applications.
- I collaborated with other team members to drive the project to successful completion.

A handful of Tool was used such as Git, Github, Pivotal Tracker, PostgreSQL, Sequelize (ORM), Nodejs, Expressjs, Reactjs, Travis, Heroku to mention a few.

EDUCATION

University Of Lagos

Dec 2008 - Dec 2014

Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

SKILLS

Nodejs, MongoDB, MongoOse, PostgreSQL, ExpressJs, TypeOrm, NestJs, Sequelize, Typescript, JavaScript, GraphQL, Restful API, TDD, Git and Github, Google cloud storage, Heroku, Object-Oriented design, Bash, Docker.

HTLM5, CSS3, Reactjs, NextJs, React-hooks, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Bootstrap, Semantic-UI, Materialize-CSS, Chakra-UI, Material-UI, TailwindCSS, CSS Preprocessor (SASS/SCSS/LESS).

Communication, Team-work, Attention to details, Adaptability, Agile Project Management.

Tools: Trello, Pivotal Tracker, Slack, Zoom, Google Meetings.